Guide to the Robert Lynch papers, 1963-1989
Lynch, Robert papers, 1963-1989
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Robert Lynch papers, 1963-1989
7320
Robert Lynch, 1947-1989
8.1 cubic ft.
Correspondence, diaries, chapbooks of poetry, financial, legal, and business records, photoprints, photo negatives, videocassettes, slides, drawings, greeting cards, and miscellaneous printed material.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
The Robert Lynch papers consist of correspondence, diaries, poems and chapbooks of unpublished poetry, and typescripts; also, financial, legal, and business records and mailings, miscellaneous collected printed material, brochures, photoprints, photo negatives, videocassettes, slides, movie films, children's drawings, greeting cards, perfunctory mailings, clippings, genealogical charts, a high school memory book, pressed wildflowers and other botanical specimens, and occasional notes left by others for Lynch.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Robert Lynch was born with the name Larry O'Neal Lynch on 14 September 1947 near Enfield, in Halifax County, eastern North Carolina. He was the oldest of the five children of Izetta Hedgepeth Lynch and Randolph Lynch. After graduating from Eastman High School in Enfield, North Carolina and the University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill, he attended Harvard Law School. After practicing as an attorney in New York City, where he specialized in corporate and securities law, he became involved with the Dance Theatre of Harlem. In August of 1975, he returned to rural North Carolina, living for a time at "Redbird Cabin," a neglected cottage in the woods not far from the home in which he was a child. Lynch referred to this as his "Thoreauvian period"; there, for an especially intensive period of four years, and for the rest of his life, he wrote poetry, kept close and introspective poetic and impressionistic diaries, and researched his complex ancestries. In the 1970s, he also travelled and hitchhiked in America and internationally, frequently visiting friends in metropolitan areas. In 1979 he moved into "Izetta House," the home in which he had grown up. By 1980 he was referring to himself as Robert Benjamin Richardson Lynch, though his family and those who had known him as Larry, continued to call him that. He also spent periods of a year or less as the Officer of Housing, Economic Development and Cultural Affairs for Princeville, North Carolina, as Development Director for WVSP Public Radio in Warrenton, North Carolina, and as a consultant to the Dance Theatre of Harlem. In the early 1980s, Lynch became involved in studying and collecting folk art, (or primitive art, or l'art brut), which he referred to as "outsider art." As a field collector and dealer, Lynch acquired examples and assembled a large photographic representation of outsider art, and also created a video on the subject. In 1987 he became aware of having contracted AIDS. Lynch died on 13 March 1989.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
The correspondence (1963-1988) consists mainly of letters to and from family members and to and from friends, particularly Paul Bridgewater, Siri V. Melchior, Michael D. Fullwood, Michelle Patrick, Ralph Hardee Rives, Wendy Walker, J. J. Hawthorne, and Vela Holmes. For a period of years (1973-1979) Lynch kept careful carbon copies of his outgoing letters, though the name of the correspondent was handwritten only on the original. In both the diaries and in his correspondence, Robert Lynch chronicled and monitored his life very closely, particularly in the years in Cambridge, and at Redbird Cabin and Izetta House. The correspondence pertains mostly to his persistent and habitual inquiry into his artistic sensibility, his constant awareness of his ancestral resonances, and to the cultural and physical environment of Redbird Cabin and Izetta House. In letters to his siblings, he is both explicit and discursive as he sorts out the relationships and pressures within and among his immediate and extended families. In one case, he includes a copy of a 1968 letter to him from his father in a 1987 letter to his sister. Family correspondence includes letters to and from his mother Izetta Lynch, signed "your mom," and sister Rhonda McFarland, and also his siblings Judith, Elliott, and Tobias. Family names used include Blie and Boy. Other correspondence deals with his relationship with Michelle Patrick, sharing news with friends, with Redbird Cabin and its conditions, and his attempt to purchase it; also Lynch's Possession of Marijuana case, his involvement with the Prison and Jail Project of North Carolina, his collecting of outsider art and the beginning of his career as an art dealer. There is minimal reference to AIDS or his illness in the correspondence. There are several letters by Lynch returned to him lacking a correct address. There are some unopened lists of job openings from the Harvard Law School Placement Service, and many never opened notices of threatened litigation from several commercial creditors referring to unpaid accounts.
Robert Lynch's diaries represent the clearest depiction of his themes and perceptions. The diaries are chiefly poetic and impressionistic, but are occasionally narrative descriptions of events, family genealogies, or his poetic observances. His appreciation of and integration with nature are evident, both in the expository descriptions, and in his custom of pasting in wildflowers, leaves, and other botanical specimens. As a reader of T. S. Eliot, Lynch notes his self-conscious searching for the proper objective correlative: "occasionally configurations coag: writing; sex; family; work; the weather as now."
As with the correspondence, 1977 was a particularly fertile period, and the diaries for this year well document Lynch's chief concerns; outstanding among these is his engagement with his plural ancestries. As a member of a miscegenated group of African-Americans, Indians, mulattoes, whites, and other racial heterogeneities, Lynch describes his searches through his ancestries as his personal "vision quest." Describing the ways in which various cousins and family members lived in this complex descendence, Lynch notes that "some passed, some called themselves indians, and some blacks." The Haliwa-Saponi tribe, centered in Halifax County, North Carolina, were also called the Meadows Indians, the "Old Issue," and "the free people of color." He refers to his matrix of consanguinity, to his "grids of kinship," and genealogical "cloverleaf interloops." The elaborate Lynch, Richardson, Bass, and Hedgepeth patrimonies and matrilineal sequences are derived, and he notes as examples of these complex inter-familial relationships that his maternal grandmother was also a Lynch, and that "brother Elliott is dating my grandmother's aunt's great-grandchild." Lynch also expresses his perception of these self-referential heritages in a poem titled "Cousin Kissing." There is too a clear awareness of the "high yella" characterization of that part of his heritage which was African-American. He also refers to the homoerotic component of the American Indians' myth-rituals, and notes its personal and historical importance.
While the diaries show him piecing together these networks both practically and poetically, with some emphasis on the impressionistic, the clearest substantive exposition of his findings is most clearly put in the correspondence of 1977 and 1978. Writing his "family/tribal history" was chief among his pursuits. He several times refers to himself as a "sharecropper's son." When he begins a diary entry with a date, he often notes that it is "Judy's birthday," or "Blie's birthday" without any other comment. He refers to his dreams of the farm. The New South and its improved racial environment are an occasional concern, and he notes that when he left Rocky Mount for Chapel Hill in 1965, "it was from the colored waiting section." Another subject of his diaries is his travel and his observations.
In the years of the Harvard diaries and subsequently, he is also preoccupied with the difficulties occasioned by what he refers to as "lust." The Harvard diaries also document Lynch's often perplexing relations with Michelle Patrick. His attraction to men is expressed as well. Though there is little manifest reference to homosexuality, he chronicles his dilemmas with social and romantic affairs, and writes frequently of his dissatisfactions pertaining to his condition of lovelessness. Some of the later correspondence is overtly erotic, and a fair amount of the poetry also shows this preoccupation.
The diaries also describe his use of valium and drug experiences closely, his reactions to Harvard social life, his visits with a psychiatrist, his efforts to have siblings admitted to New England prep schools, his health, and his attention to and appreciation of visual art, dance, and jazz. Other topics include his academic problems, including his lack of commitment to Law School or to the law, and his indifference to a career. He read widely, and the diaries regularly register his reactions to Rilke, Woolf, Warhol, and many others. Lynch made verbatim typescripts of his handwritten diaries, particularly for the Harvard years. There were concurrently running diaries, and fragments whose span dates embrace the dates of other discrete diaries. There are no extant diaries for 1973-1974. He also employed an epistolary device in the diaries, with a "Ted" as his correspondent. Certain thematic phrases recur in various pieces, including "O lost, and by the wind grieved, ghost, come back again," (by T. W.), and "what are the roots that clutch." As with the correspondence, there is in the diaries minimal mention of AIDS. There are also attached numerous pieces of ephemera, including an occasional notice of delinquent finance and a note from his mother, which evidently serve as artifacts rather than conveyors of information.
Robert Lynch noted frequently that his purpose in returning to Halifax County was to provide himself with time and to achieve a beneficent environment for the writing of his poetry. While at Harvard Law School, Lynch had studied with Robert Fitzgerald and Robert Lowell, but his work is classically imagist and haikuesque in nature. Among the many chapbooks which he composed and produced, there are very few narrative poems. Even in his expository prose, Lynch would use purely poetic images. There is evidence of fastidious reworking of some of the poems, including careful attention to metre. Though he entered the Yale Series of Younger Poets Competition to no effect, and submitted work to other publishers, apparently nothing was published.
The photoprints, negatives, and slides form three categories; family subjects, (including many he took of himself in a mirror); a collection of photos of black men, most of which are erotic; and the artworks and the outsider artists visited by Lynch during his field collecting. Very few are identified. The videos pertain to Lynch's collection of outside art.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Lynch, Robert, 1947-1989.; Lynch, Lawrence Oneal.
Subjects:
AIDS (Disease)--North Carolina.; Gay men.; Homosexuality and art.; Homosexuality, Male.; Indians of North America-- North Carolina--Halifax County.; Family--North Carolina-- Halifax County.; Harvard Law School-- Students.; Folk art--North Carolina--Halifax County.; Race awareness.; Miscegenation.; Indians--Mixed descent.; Afro-Americans--Race identity.; Indians--Mixed bloods.; Halifax County (N.C.)--Local history.
Form and Genre Terms:
Genealogies.; Poems.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Correspondence (Incoming and Outgoing)
Box 1
Series II. Writings
Boxes 1-3
Series III. Datebooks/Diaries/Notebooks
Boxes 4-18, 35
Series IV. Photographic Materials
Boxes 19-33, 36
Series V. Videocassettes
Box 34, V-213-V216
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Correspondence (Incoming and Outgoing)
  - Letter from Glenda, Apr. 10 1963 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Letter from Bertha Holmes, Aug. 20 1965 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Letters from Judith and Izetta Lynch, and from Larry Lynch to Wendy Walker, 1970-1972 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Carbon copies from Larry Lynch, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Letters from Izetta Lynch, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Letters to Michelle Patrick, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Michelle Patrick marriage announcement, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Letters to Siri V. Melchior, and others without recipient's name, May 11 1976 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Copies of letters from Larry Lynch at Redbird Cabin, Dec. 1976 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Carbon copies of outgoing letters from Larry Lynch at Redbird Cabin, Jan. 1977 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Carbon copies of outgoing letters from Larry Lynch at Redbird Cabin, Jan. 2 1977 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Letters from Ted, Siri V. Melchior, Michael D. Fullwood, J. J. Hawthorne, and from Larry Lynch, Jan. 3 1977 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Letters from Vela Holmes, Rhonda McFarland, Frances Leila McFarland, Sharon, J. J. Hawthorne, and from Larry Lynch to Michelle Patrick and Ronald Norwood, Jan. 3 1977 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Copies of letters from Larry Lynch at Redbird Cabin, Mar. 4 1977 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Letters from Siri V. Melchior, Paul Bridgewater, Wendy Walker, J. J. Hawthorne, Ralph Hardee Rives, and an anonymous letter correcting Lynch's alleged mistakes in an article in Halifax County This Week, Apr. 7 1977 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Letters from J. J. Hawthorne, Wendy Walker, Michael D. Fullwood, Fletcher and Annie L. Lynch, and Ralph Hardee Rives, May 6 1977 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Carbon copies and drafts of outgoing letters from Larry Lynch at Redbird Cabin, Jun. 7 1977 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Letters from J. J. Hawthorne, Terry Gill, and Siri V. Melchior, and outgoing letters from Larry Lynch, Jul. 1977 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Letters from J. J. Hawthorne, Vela Holmes, Ralph Hardee Rives, John McGwigan, Michael D. Fullwood, Wendy Walker, and outgoing letters from Larry Lynch, Jul. 10 1977 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Letters from Bunyan Bryant, Vela Holmes, Paul Bridgewater, and Sharon, and outgoing letters from Larry Lynch, Jul. 11 1977 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Carbon copies of outgoing letters from Larry Lynch at Redbird Cabin, Includes an Aug. 4 1977 letter discussing the Lynch ancestries, and an Aug. 17 1977 letter in which he states: "I must say it startles one's historical conception to find oneself descended of slave owners." (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Carbon copies of outgoing letters from Larry Lynch at Redbird Cabin, Sep. 1977, Letters concerning the Lynch ancestries (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Letters from Anne Melchior Scott, Fay Hauser, and Izetta Lynch, Oct. 12 1977 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Letters from Ralph Hardee Rives, Michael D. Fullwood, Izetta Lynch, Anne Melchior Scott, Siri V. Melchior, Alfred D, Lynch, and the Harvard Law School re: delinquent loan repayments, Oct. 12 1977 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Letters from Izetta Lynch, J. J. Hawthorne, Rhonda McFarland, Ralph Hardee Rives, Terry Sanford, Vela Holmes; also lists and drafts of poems, Nov. 12 1977 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Letters from Jonathan Williams, Paul Bridgewater, Jamake Highwater, Thomas La Farge, Michael D. Fullwood, Vela Holmes, Siri V. Melchior, J. J. Hawthorne, John Ashbery, and the Harvard Law School, Jan. 5 1978 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Copies of outgoing letters from Lynch at Redbird Cabin, Apr. 1978 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Copies of outgoing letters from Lynch at Redbird Cabin, 5 1978, Letters pertaining to Lynch ancestries, May 1978 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Copies of outgoing letters from Lynch at Redbird Cabin, Jun. 1978, Letters pertaining to Lynch and other forbearer ancestries (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Letters from Izetta Lynch, Michael D. Fullwood, Siri V. Melchior, Philipp von Turk, Ralph Hardee Rives, J. J. Hawthorne, Weston La Barre, Frances McFarland, Jun. 7 1978 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Letters from Weston La Barre, Rhonda McFarland, and Siri V. Melchior, Aug. 9 1978 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Letters from Siri V. Melchior, Dawn Clayton, Paul Bridgewater, J. J. Hawthorne, and John McGwigan, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Letters from Fay Hauser, Paul Bridgewater, Vela Holmes, and drafts of letters from Robert Lynch, one pertaining to his efforts to qualify for the North Carolina bar which describes the ways his life has taken, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Letters from Wendy Walker, Willie D., Gene Holloway, and Larry White, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Letters from Tony Richardson, Siri V. Melchior, Bunyan Bryant, and Willie D., 1982 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Letters from Willie D. and Siri V. Melchior, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Letters from Darryl Walden, Izetta Lynch, Bunyan Bryant, and Prison Project and WVSP correspondence, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Letter from Wendy Walker, and letter from Robert Lynch, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Letters and cards from Wendy Walker, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Letters from Sharon Epstein, Roger Manley, Jonathan Williams, and Paul Bridgewater, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Correspondence, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Letter from Paul Bridgewater, and perhaps unsent letters from Robert Lynch to Ann Shengold referring to an art exhibition, and to Chuck at the Dance Theatre of Harlem, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Letter from Robert Lynch to the Editor of The Progress re: John Mcgwigan and George Eastman, and letters to Charles Lane re: the "Robert Lynch Collection Of Outsider Art"; also letters from Judith Lynch, Randolph Lynch, Barbara Archer of The High Museum Of Art in Atlanta, Ann Shengold re: an art exhibition, and a proposal to WVSP from Robert Lynch, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Letter from the Duke University Medical Center re: Robert Lynch's test use of Oral Retrovir, and letters from Roger Manley, Wendy Walker, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Two envelopes of slips of paper with names, addresses, and phone numbers, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Letters from John McGwigan and to Michelle Patrick, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Letters from Anthony Moto, Tom Walden, Izetta Lynch, Cary P. Bell, and Peter Edward Bent, and postcards from Larry Lynch, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 47)
- Series II. Writings
  - Poems, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Poems, drafts of letters, diary fragments, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Diary pages, Jun. 8 1969 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Typescript of diary, Jul. 8 1969 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Typescript of diary, Sep. 1969-May 1970 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Poems, including "Cat In Gloves", Oct. 1969-Apr. 1970 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Poems, poem fragments and re-workings, notes, Nov. 1969-Jan. 1970 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Poems, drafts Of "Cat In Gloves", Nov. 1969-May 1970 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Poems: "Cat In Gloves," "To Izetta Mon Fils, Quel Monstre!"; drafts of letters and essays, lists, notes, Feb. 1970 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Essay, poems, diary entries, notes, Feb. 3 1970 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Poems, draft of "Cat In Gloves", Mar. 4 1970 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Typescript of diary, Apr. 8 1970 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Typescript of diary, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Poems, Oct. 1970 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Diary pages, Dec. 1970-Apr. 1972; notes for poems (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - The poem "Cat In Gloves" in The Harvard Advocate, Jan. 1971 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Typescript of diary, May 1971-Feb. 1972 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Typescript of diary, Mar. 7 1972 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Diary pages, Oct. 1975-Jan. 1977; draft of a letter to Fitzgerald (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Poems and fragments of diary entries, Dec. 1976-Jan. 1977 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Draft of a story, poems, and drafts of an essay "What Are The Roots That Clutch" concerning Lynch's memories of his childhood and his family's narrative history and traditions, Jan. 2 1977 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Poems, drafts of diary entries, drafts of an essay, Jan. 2 1977 (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Prose, in letter form, concerning life at Redbird Cabin, ca. Feb. 1977 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Drafts of "What Are The Roots That Clutch," ca. Feb. 1977 (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Poems, prose pieces, and drafts of "Rattling Eliotic Bones" and "O Lost, and by the Wind Grieved, Ghost, Come Back Again", ca. Feb. 1977 (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Article by Lynch in Halifax County This Week concerning his family history and personal ancestries, May 26 1977 (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Draft of prose poem "Atmospheric Suburbs" - scroll, Nov. 1977 (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Drafts of poems, drafts of diary entries, and drafts of letters, Dec. 1977 (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Sonnets; vita, ca. Dec. 1977 (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - Prose writings: "A Family Excursion" and "Making It Back Then", 1977 (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Prose writings: "I Received a Superlative Education at White Oak School," "Brer Rabbit and the Terrapin," "A Lovesong," and drafts of the poem "Timothy Three", 1977 (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - Prose writings, and drafts of "Timothy Three", 1977 (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - Drafts of poems, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 80)
  - Poems, drafts of poems, draft of a letter, Apr. 5 1978 (Box 1, Folder 81)
  - Poems, drafts of poems, Apr. 5 1978 (Box 1, Folder 82)
  - Drafts of poems, May 1978 (Box 1, Folder 83)
  - Poems, drafts of poems, ca. May 1978 (Box 1, Folder 84)
  - Part of a letter/prospectus re: Lynch ancestries, ca. May 1978 (Box 1, Folder 85)
  - Typescript of diary, May 6 1978 (Box 1, Folder 86)
  - Drafts of poems, May 6 1978 (Box 1, Folder 87)
  - Drafts of poems, prose writings, Jun. 1978 (Box 1, Folder 88)
  - Drafts of poems, Jun. 11 1978 (Box 1, Folder 89)
  - Poems, Sep. 1978 (Box 1, Folder 90)
  - Drafts of poems, Oct.-Nov. 1978 (Box 1, Folder 91)
  - Poems and drafts of poems, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 92)
  - Poems and notes for poems, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 93)
  - Draft of a Letter to the Editor, ca. 1978 (Box 1, Folder 94)
  - "A Proposal To The National Endowment For The Humanities To Research And Develop A Series Of Radio Broadcasts: 'Under All Is The Land: A Series On Land Ownership, Use, And Exchange In The Rural South'," ca. 1978-79 (Box 1, Folder 95)
  - Draft "A Proposal To The National Endowment Of The Humanities: 'Black Land Loss And Related Agricultural Problems'," ca. 1978-79 (Box 1, Folder 96-97)
  - Drafts of poems, Jan. 1979 (Box 1, Folder 98)
  - Drafts of poems, Feb.-Mar. 1979 (Box 1, Folder 99)
  - Drafts of poems and a prose poem, Mar. 1979 (Box 1, Folder 100)
  - Princeville Facilities and Services Report, Jun. 1979 (Box 1, Folder 101)
  - Drafts of poems, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 102)
  - The Redbird Poems, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 103-106)
  - Drafts of The Redbird Poems, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 107)
  - Nine Songs, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 108)
  - Drafts of The Redbird Poems, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 109)
  - Songs To My Self, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 110)
  - Drafts of poems, "Redbird, Redbird, Lay In My Hand", 1979 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Drafts of poems, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 2-3)
  - Drafts of "Bye Blackbird", May 1980 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - The Lover, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - In A Huge Temple, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Joint Pieces, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - The Brides/Sonnets, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 8-10)
  - All Sorts, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Worked In, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Writings, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Harlem Suite, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - What's That?, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - What Wanting, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Selection of poems from various chapbooks serving as specimens for a North Carolina Arts Council Writer's Fellowship application, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Summer In Spring/Final Sonnets, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - The Anthony Poems, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Selected Poems (1975-1988) (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - As It Is/Briefer Sonnets, Switcheroo/Briefer Sonnets, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Ask No Man, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - An Addendum To Love (More Anthony Poems), 1988 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - The Jessica Songs/The Jessica Poems, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 24)